Why'd you set it
for the day before yesterday?
Because I wanna go back and keep myself
from getting a time machine.
(Sheldon:)You can't. If you were to prevent yourself
from buying it in the past...
(Sheldon:)...you would not have it available
to stop yourself from buying it.
(Sheldon:)Ergo, you would still have it.
This is a classic rookie time-travel mistake.
(Leonard:)Can I go back and prevent you
from explaining that to me?
(Sheldon:)Same paradox.
(Sheldon:)If you were to travel back in time
and knock me unconscious...
...you wouldn't have the conversation
that irritated you...
(Sheldon:)...motivating you to go back
and knock me unconscious.
(Leonard:)What if I knocked you unconscious
right now?
(Sheldon:)It won't change the past.
But it'd make the present so much nicer.
(Sheldon:)Are you upset about something?
(Leonard:)What was your first clue?
(Sheldon:)Well, it was a number of things.
First, the late hour.
Then your demeanor
seems very low-energy.
(Sheldon:)- Plus your irritability...
- Yes, I'm upset.
(Howard:)Oh.
(Sheldon:)I don't usually pick up on those things.